today we're gonna take a look at how to
do advanced editing in Final Cut Pro X
so stick around hey what's up guys is
Marcos and this channel is all about
helping you create better video so you
can build your brand so if you're new to
this channel subscribe right now so you
don't miss a thing
alright so before we get started if you
haven't already watched my learn Final
Cut Pro X in 13 minutes watch that video
first because it will give you an
introduction into using Final Cut Pro X
so that's for beginners once you watch
that come back to this video because I'm
gonna go over some very advanced editing
features in Final Cut Pro X so without
further ado let's jump over to computer
and let's get started
here we are in my desktop and this is my
external hard drive I would highly
recommend that you always save your
video footage and your audio to an
external hard drive don't store on your
computer otherwise it's gonna slow it
down all right so here's a bunch of
folders these are videos that I've
worked on in the past these are all my
YouTube videos I always start by
creating a new folder whenever I'm
working on a project so the important
thing about advanced editing is having a
workflow so this is my workflow I create
folder for each project so let's take a
look at one of these like this jump-cuts
let's say I just imported all my video
footage and my audio for audio
recordings here I'm gonna be creating a
new project out of this footage alright
so I start by importing and then I have
to keep track of which audio corresponds
to which video clip so zero zero seven
corresponds to zoom zero zero one that's
very important to be aware of that
because we're going to be syncing this
audio with the video so let's start by
opening up Final Cut Pro X
let's maximize this alright so by
default if Final Cut Pro X will open the
last project we worked on but we want to
close everything otherwise our computer
will slow down since it's trying to
manage multiple projects so we want to
close it the closes down this is our
last project file close library DIY
quick release you want to have like this
whenever you're starting a new project
you don't want to have anything open so
go to file new actually I'm gonna skip
over this because you probably already
know how to do all of this alright so
command I to import footage you'll
notice that I did not create optimized
media I think my computer handles 4k
footage just fine without creating
optimized media so let's sync the audio
z 0 0 7 corresponds to zoom 0 0 1 you
hold on the command button or key and
you tap it right click synchronize clips
and you want to use the audio for
synchronization click OK and let's drag
this over to our timeline and I'm gonna
change the view of this because I want
to see the audio you can do something
like that or like this so first of all
we have to turn off the audio coming off
the camera otherwise it's gonna sound
bad so if we unchecked storyline that's
how you know it turns off the audio from
the camera and you only keep the
connected which is assumed h1 which is
what we want
alright so to close down windows you
want to do this as much as you can
because you'll have more space to work
with
let's close down the library control
command 1 command 4 to close the
inspector command 4 to open it up again
and then command 5 is for the video and
audio effects like transitions and that
and sometimes it's better to just have
it closed until you need it
command 5 to close that alright so let's
see here there's a bunch of dead space
here this is where I began talking so
one of the things you need to learn
about is keyboard shortcuts try to use
them as much as you can so we don't have
to use
our mouth so try to keep this mouth up
here because if if you have your mouth
up down here it might interfere with the
keyboard shortcut so keep it up here so
to go to the beginning of this video hit
the up arrow key and now to fast-forward
hold down the shift and the right arrow
key and it'll fast-forward to the right
now to move one frame at a time just hit
the right arrow key I want to bring the
video clip over to the right so hold
down the option left bracket key and it
moves everything to the right now let's
say I want to make cut now let me move
forward in this timeline and I want to
make a cut here because there's death
space so instead of hitting the or
grabbing your blade to just hit command
V it makes a cut there now to fast
forward shift right arrow key or shift
left arrow key to fast-forward to the
left now let's drag the clip again to
the left or to the right actually option
left bracket key and you can do the same
thing let's say I'm gonna do fast
forward I'm gonna make a cut here
command B or command Z to undo whenever
you mess up shift alright lets me let me
make a cut here command B and then I'm
gonna move to the left shift right there
we go and I'm gonna bring the the clip
to the left so option right bracket key
it brings everything to the left so
that's how it works
if you want to zoom in command + command
- command + to zoom in command minus to
zoom out you can also use let's see if
I'm really sumed in here and I want to
do a fast zoom out shift C and I'll
bring all the timeline into view now
that we have that let's move on to color
grading - color great faster I like to
use an adjustment layer and I'll link to
a video where you can get an adjustment
layer so ctrl command 1 to open our
library and here's the custom adjustment
layer you can drag this over and we're
gonna be applying the color grade to all
of our footage
using this adjustment layer alright
command 6 to open up the colors wheels
there it is
control command 1 to 2 close that down
the other thing down command 7 is to
open up these scopes which I use a lot
now I'm not gonna go over color grading
that's a whole different topic and I can
spend you know 20 minutes just explain
it so I'll link to other videos check
out this videos here and also I'll leave
some links in the description so you can
check out how to color great so
basically the idea is to add some color
grade here to add more contrast
there's our highlights I can add
saturation there and our image is
already looking better so you can check
this to see the difference I shot this
in NASA log 2 which is a flat picture
profile so you know you just have to do
some tweaking to it to get the colors
out alright so come in command 7 to open
up scopes you can also change the view
to the vectorscope and different
waveforms a histogram and all I don't
use a histogram that much I use a wave
form in the vectorscope again check out
the videos on how to color great and you
can also what you do is let's say I'm
using this setup often and I'm using the
same lights same settings on my camera I
can save the effects preset that way
whenever I come back to edit something
to color grade I can just select this
preset in it'll automatically color
great for me so I already have some here
folder which I use often whenever I'm do
using this setup because I save time
with the color grading so think about
that whenever you're you're shooting
anything try to use the same settings
and have the same repeatable workflow
that way it speeds up your editing
process lastly I just want to go over
some very helpful keyboard shortcuts
which are gonna help you save time again
let me close the scopes and let me close
the inspector so to add a title is ctrl
T whenever you're editing editing a
title make sure your playhead is over
your title command for again to open it
I am always opening and closing the
inspector and all those windows
and you go here to change the text you
probably already know that and you can
also make a copy of this title by
selecting it holding down the option key
and dragging it over sometimes you need
to create multiple titles and that makes
it easier to create copies at the same
title to add a transition between two
Clips like I have here make sure that
this is selected command T to add the
default transition and we zoom in here
you can see we can drag this make it
shorter make it longer that's up to us
to decide also whenever let's say I'm
doing key framing like this how this
title let's say I wanted to slide it in
you go up arrow key to go to the
beginning and we're gonna add some key
frames here you can add it to the x-axis
so we add a keyframe there and let's
move it out of place there we go now
let's move forward like ten frames shift
right arrow key chef's shift arrow right
arrow key we move ten frames and then
let's not add another keyframe and let's
go to the center by hitting the zero
enter so if we play this it moves you
see that and if you want to change the
key framing you can do control V select
the title clip control V and it will
show us the the animation so we can drag
this keyframe to the to the left you
want if you want it to slide in much
faster so play it you see that or if we
want it to go really slow you see that
so that's really neat to do that you can
always say oh I don't like this this
title at all I just want to get rid of
it you can just select the V button and
it'll you know disable it because let's
say you change your mind and you want to
come back to it so that's an option I
want to show you two more things before
I end this video one of them is how to
crop in so let's say I want to make a
cut here again let's not use our
playhead let's move to the left make a
cut here command B and I want to zoom in
to this video on a scale and we could go
to the inspector and
use the sliders over here but personally
I like to use this here and what I like
to do is actually zoom out maybe like 25
percent and then I can just drag this
over and what I'm doing is zooming in or
copying the image actually not actually
cropping but zooming in and then I can
reposition this wherever I want I can
zoom out if I needed to I just flip the
image I don't want that and just
reposition it and make sure that these
lines or that my video is not
accidentally cropped in the wrong way
otherwise we're gonna have black bars so
that's why I like to soup mount just to
make sure my whole video is taking over
the the space I have set okay so that
looks good click done you can go back to
fit and there you go I assumed in from
this to this I assumed it that's pretty
neat the other thing you can do is
create a freeze-frame sometimes let's
say you want to just freeze part of your
screen you can select it make sure your
playhead is where you want it to be go
to edit add freeze frame and here it
just froze up this image and you can
extend this or make it shorter it's up
to you so that's something that you
might use once in a while it's good to
know about it so those are the major
things I use and I like to keep it
simple and fast and those are the things
whenever you can try to learn the
keyboard shortcuts like for the freeze
frame is you can see here it's that's
shift F I think that's shift let me see
no it's that means option F there it is
it's option F so whenever you can like I
said have those in mind or right in
somewhere so you can quickly refer to
them and eventually they become a habit
and you can edit much faster alright so
those are the features I use most often
I know there's a bunch of other stuff
but this is the stuff that I find the
most useful and that I use almost every
time I sit down to edit so please let me
know if you have questions any comments
anything you I wasn't clear about please
let me know down in the comments
action also if you liked this video
please let me know by hitting the like
button if you haven't already subscribed
please go ahead and do so because I'm
making videos like this every week and
you don't want to miss it
as always guys I want to thank you for
watching and I'll see you on the next
video
[Music]